Guide to the Congress of American Professors Records TAM.043
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Congress of American Professors Records
1967
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Congress of American Professors
Fields, George
TAM.043
0.5 Linear Feet (1 box)
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by George Fields in 1970. The accession number associated with this gift is 1970.004.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Historical/Biographical Note
The Congress of American Professors, a New Left group, was organized in 1967 to consider policy and action alternatives in key areas of vital national concern. The center of activity was Columbia University, where Professor Seymour Melman played a prominent role.
Scope and Content Note
The records contain correspondence, calls for a conference scheduled for December 1967, statements of purpose, minutes, lists of supporters and material from conferences and meetings, including a preparatory meeting at Columbia University's Mudd Hall, in March 1967.
Arrangement
The folders are arranged alphabetically.
The files are grouped into one series:
Missing Title
I, Records, 1967
College teachers -- Political activity -- United States.; Correspondence.; Minutes (administrative records); New Left -- United States.; Congress of American Professors; Melman, Seymour; Fields, George
- Series I: Records, 1967.
  - Address Lists: New York and Planning Committees, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Call (May) Drafts, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Call (May) Replies, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Call (August) Mailing, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Columbia University: Mudd Hall Conference (March), 1967 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: General, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: "Nita" (Seymour Melman's Secretary), 1967 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Contacts outside New York, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Letters to Call Signers (September), 1967 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - New York Committee (September), 1967 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - New York Group Correspondence, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - New York Group Meetings, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Newsletter (plans before first issue), 1967 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Other Organizations, Information on, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Outside Appeals, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Plans for December Conference, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 16)